<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Against The Tide</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Against The Tide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/hugo-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/hugo-tips/</guid>
      <description>Useful tips for working with Hugo static sites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Blog Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/first-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/first-blog/</guid>
      <description>This is a mock article for testing the new blog section.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Journalism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/journalism-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/journalism-future/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts on where journalism is heading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Use Org-mode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/why-orgmode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/why-orgmode/</guid>
      <description>Org-mode is the backbone of my writing workflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hodeidah 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/50-20-hodeidah-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/50-20-hodeidah-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In the early hours of April 8, 2025, suspected U.S. airstrikes hit the al-Hawak district of Hodeidah, a critical Red Sea port city.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Fatimah Al-Saqaf, a teacher and mother of three, was preparing breakfast when explosions shook her apartment building. One strike demolished a warehouse across the street, sending shrapnel into nearby homes. Her daughter was injured by glass, and neighbors rushed to dig survivors from the rubble.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The strikes killed at least eight civilians and injured 16, according to Houthi health officials. Local footage showed chaos as ambulances navigated debris-laden streets lit by cellphone flashlights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saada 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/51-43-saada-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/51-43-saada-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Saada, a Houthi stronghold, came under intense bombardment in March 2025 as part of a U.S. air campaign.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Hussein Sharaf, a shopkeeper, lost his wife and daughter when their home was struck. He returned from evening prayers to find rubble where his house stood. He later buried his family in the city’s crowded cemetery, which overflowed with civilian casualties.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Journalists visiting Saada reported entire blocks flattened and a surge in amputations at local hospitals overwhelmed by trauma cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sanaa 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/52-45-sanaa-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/52-45-sanaa-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;On March 15, 2025, U.S. and allied forces launched a large-scale bombing campaign on Houthi targets in Sanaa, Yemen’s capital.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Aisha al-Mutairi, a pediatrician, was tending patients when missiles struck a nearby arms depot. The shockwave collapsed part of the children’s hospital wing. She pulled two infants from rubble and worked overnight to stabilize the injured with dwindling supplies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Her account, circulated by Doctors Without Borders, illustrated the humanitarian cost of renewed U.S. involvement in Yemen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Al Shabab Camp 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/49-03-al-shabab-camp-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/49-03-al-shabab-camp-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In February 2022, U.S. Africa Command confirmed an airstrike targeting al-Shabaab militants in Somalia. While officials claimed precision, local reports suggested civilian structures were damaged.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Asha Mohamed, a herder’s wife, said a nearby livestock shelter was destroyed, killing over 20 goats and injuring her nephew. They lived a few kilometers from the alleged militant camp.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;U.S. officials maintained no civilian deaths occurred. Human rights monitors disputed this, citing lack of transparency in assessments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Al Bayda 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/48-01-al-bayda-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/48-01-al-bayda-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;U.S. drone strikes targeted alleged AQAP operatives in Al Bayda province. Locals reported civilian casualties, including two boys riding a motorbike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Fadhl al-Rimi, a schoolteacher, recognized one of the bodies as his student. He said the boys were heading to a village market when the missile struck.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;He later testified to human rights groups that no militants were in the area. His school was closed for two weeks in mourning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baghouz 2019</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/47-06-baghouz-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/47-06-baghouz-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;As ISIS made its last stand in Baghouz, U.S. warplanes dropped massive ordnance on makeshift camps where fighters and civilians were mixed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Um Yasir, a Syrian mother of three, had taken refuge in a tent when the bombing began. Her youngest daughter died instantly. Um Yasir survived with burns and shrapnel wounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Investigative reports later revealed that the U.S. failed to disclose the strike, which may have killed over 80 people. Her story was documented by journalists who arrived weeks after the area was secured.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Al Qaim 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/42-02-al-qaim-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/42-02-al-qaim-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Al-Qaim, near the Syrian border, was one of ISIS’s final strongholds. The U.S.-led coalition launched heavy air raids ahead of the Iraqi army’s advance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Mahmoud al-Salim, a baker, recounted baking bread when a blast shattered his storefront. He woke up in a hospital in Haditha, missing his right hand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;After the battle, he returned to find the neighborhood razed. Many civilians had been unable to evacuate, and their fates remained unrecorded in official tallies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deir Ez Zor 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/43-11-deir-ez-zor-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/43-11-deir-ez-zor-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;As the Syrian government and U.S.-backed forces closed in on ISIS in Deir ez-Zor, the city was heavily bombarded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Ahmad Hariri, a vegetable vendor, lost his wife and two sons when a coalition strike hit a bridge they were crossing. He survived only because he had turned back to retrieve his cart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Ahmad told foreign journalists that no ISIS forces were present at the time—just displaced families trying to flee. His story became part of a broader investigation into civilian casualties during the Deir ez-Zor campaign.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mosul 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/44-34-mosul-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/44-34-mosul-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The U.S.-backed campaign to liberate Mosul from ISIS involved extensive airstrikes from late 2016 to mid-2017. Residential areas were often caught in the crossfire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Nadwa al-Jubouri, a widow with three children, lived in western Mosul. In March 2017, her apartment building was hit by a coalition strike targeting ISIS fighters. Her son was killed instantly, and her leg was crushed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;She was evacuated to a refugee camp and later told her story to humanitarian groups. The U.S. acknowledged civilian casualties but claimed efforts were made to minimize them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raqqa 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/45-41-raqqa-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/45-41-raqqa-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;During the battle to retake Raqqa from ISIS, the U.S.-led coalition launched thousands of airstrikes, leaving 80% of the city in ruins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Faisal Hamoud, a carpenter, returned to Raqqa after the fighting ended. His home was destroyed and four of his neighbors had died in a strike meant for an ISIS commander.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;He lived in a tent on the ruins of his house, trying to rebuild with salvaged wood. His story, captured in international news reports, highlighted the human toll of precision warfare in urban zones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabqa 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/46-47-tabqa-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/46-47-tabqa-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The U.S. provided air cover during the Syrian Democratic Forces’ offensive to capture Tabqa from ISIS. Airstrikes were frequent in the lead-up to the dam’s capture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Nisreen al-Taha, an engineer, was working on a maintenance team at the Euphrates Dam. A strike hit an outer facility, killing several coworkers and damaging key electrical controls.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Fearing a dam collapse, she joined other engineers in stabilizing the structure under fire. Her account appeared in international reports on how infrastructure was imperiled by U.S. bombings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manbij 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/40-30-manbij-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/40-30-manbij-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Manbij was the site of intense U.S.-led coalition bombing during the campaign to expel ISIS from northern Syria.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Rasha Mahfouz, a teacher, remained in the city to care for her ill father. One afternoon, a bomb struck a residential block next to their home. Her father was killed by falling debris, and Rasha sustained a head injury.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;She later gave testimony to human rights groups detailing the indiscriminate nature of the airstrikes. Entire families were buried under collapsed homes as the frontlines shifted rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sirte 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/41-46-sirte-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/41-46-sirte-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;During the campaign to oust ISIS from Sirte, U.S. aircraft carried out over 500 airstrikes between August and December 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Salwa Ben Gassem, a midwife, was caught in the crossfire when an airstrike hit a building two doors from her clinic. The shockwave ruptured her eardrum and injured a newborn baby she was helping deliver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;After the campaign, she joined a community-led effort to establish a new field hospital. Much of Sirte’s medical infrastructure was destroyed during the bombing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kunduz 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/38-29-kunduz-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/38-29-kunduz-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;A U.S. AC-130 gunship bombed a Médecins Sans Frontières (Doctors Without Borders) trauma hospital in Kunduz, Afghanistan, killing 42 people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Dr. Hamid Ullah was on a night shift when the first shells hit. The ICU caught fire, and he struggled to rescue unconscious patients. The strike continued for over 30 minutes despite MSF&amp;#39;s warnings to military officials.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;U.S. authorities later called it a “mistake,” but survivors like Dr. Ullah viewed it as a failure of accountability. The hospital was the only major trauma center in northeastern Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tikrit 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/39-48-tikrit-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/39-48-tikrit-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;U.S. aircraft supported Iraqi forces retaking Tikrit from ISIS with heavy airstrikes that targeted entrenched militant positions in the city center.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Hussein Ali, a barber, had returned briefly to his shop to collect supplies when the bombing resumed. A nearby ISIS weapons depot exploded, throwing him into a wall. He survived with a broken arm and severe burns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The city was eventually liberated, but much of the civilian infrastructure was lost. Hussein’s shop, where three generations of his family had worked, was never rebuilt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Waziristan 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/37-37-north-waziristan-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/37-37-north-waziristan-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In a rare instance, a U.S. drone strike killed a tribal elder just days before he was to lead peace talks with the Pakistani government.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Malik Jalal narrowly escaped the strike, but his driver and bodyguard were killed. Jalal later claimed he had been placed on a U.S. kill list in error.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The incident fueled Pakistani outrage over drone operations and disrupted negotiations with tribal communities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebureauinvestigates.com/stories/2016-04-21/the-man-on-the-drone-programs-hit-list&#34;&gt;Bureau of Investigative Journalism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khashamir 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/36-25-khashamir-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/36-25-khashamir-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;On the day of his wedding, Salem bin Ali Jaber, a cleric and vocal opponent of al-Qaeda, was killed in a U.S. drone strike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;He had been summoned to meet suspected militants for a theological debate. As he approached the mosque, a missile struck, killing him and three others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;His cousin, who witnessed the attack, later filed legal complaints in Germany and the U.S., arguing Salem was deliberately targeted despite his anti-extremist views.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kunar 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/35-28-kunar-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/35-28-kunar-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In March 2011, a U.S. helicopter gunship attack killed nine Afghan boys gathering firewood in Kunar Province.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Rafiq Rahmani, 12, survived with shrapnel wounds. He described how his younger brother was blown apart by the first missile. The boys had gone to collect wood after school, wearing bright-colored clothes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;General David Petraeus issued an apology, but local villagers protested for days. Rafiq left school afterward and never returned, haunted by survivor’s guilt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marjah 2010</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/34-31-marjah-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/34-31-marjah-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;During Operation Moshtarak, U.S. Marines launched a major offensive in Marjah, involving heavy aerial bombardment to retake the town from Taliban control.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Amina Baloch, a mother of five, was preparing dinner when her neighbor’s house was flattened by a precision-guided missile. Her 12-year-old son was wounded by shrapnel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;She spent three nights in a trench with her children before they were evacuated by Red Crescent volunteers. The U.S. claimed success in routing insurgents, but many residents like Amina returned to find their homes in ruins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bala Balok 2009</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/33-07-bala-balok-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/33-07-bala-balok-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;On May 4, 2009, U.S. airstrikes in Bala Baluk District, Farah Province, killed over 140 civilians according to Afghan officials.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Haji Nader Khan, a village elder, lost his daughter and three grandchildren when their home was obliterated. The village’s mud-brick houses offered no protection against 2,000-pound bombs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;He later testified to international media about the mass graves hastily dug to bury victims. The Pentagon acknowledged civilian casualties but disputed the scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mogadishu 2007</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/32-33-mogadishu-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/32-33-mogadishu-2007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;During a U.S.-supported Ethiopian military campaign, Mogadishu was subjected to aerial strikes targeting Islamist insurgents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Abdirahman Warsame, a university student, was in class when explosions rocked the Bakara Market area. Though his school was not hit, his family’s home was reduced to rubble.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;They later joined thousands of internally displaced Somalis in camps outside the city. Years later, Abdirahman became a lawyer advocating for accountability for foreign military actions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hrw.org/report/2007/12/07/so-much-fear/war-crimes-ethio-somali&#34;&gt;Human Rights Watch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haditha 2005</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/31-16-haditha-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/31-16-haditha-2005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;While not an aerial bombardment, the Haditha killings followed a roadside bombing that led U.S. Marines to storm civilian homes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Yassir Walid, 10, hid under his bed when his parents and sister were shot in their living room. He was the only survivor in his household. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;His account helped trigger a major investigation and eventually a congressional inquiry into rules of engagement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://content.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,1191826,00.html&#34;&gt;Time Magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fallujah 2004</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/30-14-fallujah-2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/30-14-fallujah-2004/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Fallujah saw two major battles between U.S. forces and insurgents. In November 2004, the U.S. launched Operation Phantom Fury, deploying heavy artillery, airstrikes, and white phosphorus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Samar al-Dulaimi, a teacher, remained in the city with her disabled father. During the bombing, their home collapsed. Trapped for 12 hours under the rubble, she was rescued by neighbors but her father did not survive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Much of the city was flattened. Over 800 civilians were killed, and more than half the population displaced. Fallujah became a symbol of urban warfare&amp;#39;s cost to civilians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baghdad 2003</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/29-05-baghdad-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/29-05-baghdad-2003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The “shock and awe” campaign marked the start of the U.S.-led invasion of Iraq. On March 20, 2003, Baghdad was blanketed with explosions as over 1,700 air sorties were launched in a single day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Khalid al-Janabi, a pharmacist, was watching television with his children when the first strike hit a government complex two blocks away. The windows shattered. Fearing for their lives, the family fled to their basement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Al-Janabi&amp;#39;s pharmacy was later destroyed in a fire caused by a misfired missile. He salvaged medicines and distributed them for free in his neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khost 2002</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/28-27-khost-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/28-27-khost-2002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In 2002, U.S. forces bombed Khost as part of a wider campaign to dismantle Taliban and al-Qaeda hideouts along the Pakistan border.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Zakir Ahmad, a school principal, was attending evening prayers when a bomb struck a compound believed to house militants nearby. The explosion blew out the mosque’s windows and injured three worshippers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Zakir later led efforts to rebuild the school, which was damaged in the blast. Many in Khost expressed confusion and anger over the lack of distinction between militant and civilian sites during the raids.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derunta 2001</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/22-12-derunta-2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/22-12-derunta-2001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The U.S. targeted the Derunta training complex in the early days of its air campaign in Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Hakim Noor, a teenager at the time, lived in a nearby farming village. A misfired bomb struck a field instead of the training camp, killing several farmhands harvesting wheat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;His father, who worked those fields for decades, helped bury the victims in a hillside cemetery. Hakim later moved to Jalalabad, never returning to farm again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jalalabad 2001</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/23-22-jalalabad-2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/23-22-jalalabad-2001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Jalalabad, an eastern Afghan city, was bombed as part of U.S. efforts to flush out al-Qaeda fighters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Mohammad Younis, a farmer, lost his brother when a U.S. bomb hit a suspected militant hideout near their orchard. The blast leveled the compound and damaged surrounding homes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In interviews with NGOs, Younis insisted his family had no militant ties. Many locals expressed resentment over indiscriminate bombings, which they believed targeted tribes opposed to the Taliban.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kabul 2001</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/24-23-kabul-2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/24-23-kabul-2001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In response to the September 11 attacks, the U.S. launched Operation Enduring Freedom, beginning with airstrikes on Taliban-controlled Kabul.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Zarmina Gul, a mother of four, lived near a military barracks. When the bombing started, the shockwaves shattered windows and ignited a nearby oil store. Her home caught fire, and she fled with her children through thick smoke.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Gul’s youngest daughter suffered burns, and local hospitals were overwhelmed. Kabul’s infrastructure was fragile; the air campaign exacerbated an already dire humanitarian crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kandahar 2001</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/25-24-kandahar-2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/25-24-kandahar-2001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;As the Taliban’s spiritual capital, Kandahar was heavily bombed in late 2001. Key facilities, including mosques and Red Crescent clinics, were damaged.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Fatima Achakzai, a schoolteacher, was inside a girls&amp;#39; school when a bomb struck nearby. Windows shattered and debris injured several students. Her classroom ceiling collapsed, but she shielded a child from falling rubble.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;After the Taliban fled, she reopened classes in tents. She became an advocate for girls&amp;#39; education despite trauma and instability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mazar I Sharif 2001</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/26-32-mazar-i-sharif-2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/26-32-mazar-i-sharif-2001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;U.S. air support played a pivotal role in the Northern Alliance&amp;#39;s capture of Mazar-i-Sharif. The city was bombed repeatedly before Taliban forces withdrew.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Farzana Nazari, a baker’s daughter, remembered sheltering with 15 others in their basement. A nearby Taliban command post was hit, sending concrete flying through her kitchen. Her cousin lost an eye from shrapnel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;When the city fell, Farzana emerged to find half the market burned and the bakery shuttered. The bombing campaign hastened liberation but left scars across the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tora Bora 2001</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/27-50-tora-bora-2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/27-50-tora-bora-2001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In December 2001, the U.S. launched an intense bombardment of Tora Bora, a mountainous area where Osama bin Laden was believed to be hiding.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Abdul Ghafar, a goat herder, lived on the lower slopes when the air campaign began. Fearing for his family, he fled with his wife and three children into nearby caves. They survived on dried fruit and melted snow for five days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Though the strikes failed to capture bin Laden, they displaced thousands of families like Ghafar’s. His livestock were lost, and his home was destroyed in the bombings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belgrade 1999</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/20-09-belgrade-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/20-09-belgrade-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;During NATO’s bombing of Yugoslavia, led by the U.S., Belgrade faced weeks of strikes targeting infrastructure and media centers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Jelena Matic, a TV technician, was working at Radio Television Serbia when the building was hit by a NATO missile. Sixteen of her colleagues were killed. She was buried under rubble for hours before being rescued.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The attack drew controversy, as critics argued it violated international law by targeting civilian broadcasters. Matic suffered permanent injuries and never returned to the studio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pristina 1999</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/21-39-pristina-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/21-39-pristina-1999/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Pristina, the capital of Kosovo, was heavily bombed during NATO’s intervention in the Yugoslav Wars.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Arta Bunjaku, a teenager, sheltered in her school’s basement with dozens of neighbors. When an electricity substation was destroyed, the city was plunged into darkness for days. Her uncle, a mechanic, died when a missile struck a nearby bus station.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;After the bombing ended, Arta emerged to find her neighborhood flattened. She later worked with UNHCR as a translator, helping displaced families recount their experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baghdad 1991</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/18-04-baghdad-1991/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1991 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/18-04-baghdad-1991/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;During the first Gulf War, U.S. and coalition forces launched a massive air campaign on Baghdad. On January 17, 1991, air raid sirens pierced the night as bombs began falling across the capital.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Layla Hassan, a university student, was in her dormitory when the power went out. Moments later, a nearby telecommunications center was struck, shaking the building. She and her friends huddled in the dark, listening to the roar of jets and the thunder of explosions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basra 1991</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/19-08-basra-1991/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1991 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/19-08-basra-1991/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Basra, Iraq’s southern port city, was heavily bombed during the final stages of the Gulf War. The U.S. targeted military units retreating from Kuwait and key infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Ali Jassim, a 19-year-old conscript, was stationed near the outskirts when cluster bombs hit his convoy. He survived by diving into a roadside ditch, but dozens of fellow soldiers were killed. Later, he described scenes of devastation—burned-out tanks, dead animals, and oil fires turning the sky black.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Panama City 1989</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/17-38-panama-city-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1989 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/17-38-panama-city-1989/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In Operation Just Cause, the U.S. invaded Panama to depose General Manuel Noriega. The bombing of Panama City began on December 20, 1989.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Maria Teresa Delgado, a seamstress, lived in the El Chorrillo district, which was near the Panamanian Defense Forces headquarters. As U.S. AC-130 gunships and F-117s opened fire, her home caught fire. She fled with her elderly mother and spent the night hiding under a bridge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The bombing destroyed much of El Chorrillo. Human rights groups estimated hundreds of civilians were killed, though exact numbers remain disputed. Maria returned to find her home reduced to ashes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benghazi 1986</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/15-10-benghazi-1986/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 1986 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/15-10-benghazi-1986/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Alongside Tripoli, Benghazi was bombed by U.S. forces during Operation El Dorado Canyon. Airstrikes targeted military barracks and communications hubs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Salem Qaddafi, a night guard at a municipal warehouse, was injured when a blast shattered glass doors and ignited a fuel tank nearby. He recalled running from the building as flames consumed adjacent blocks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The attack shocked the Libyan population and drew condemnation from several international allies, sparking protests across North Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tripoli 1986</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/16-51-tripoli-1986/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 1986 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/16-51-tripoli-1986/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In retaliation for the Berlin discotheque bombing, the U.S. launched Operation El Dorado Canyon, striking Tripoli and Benghazi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Khadija El-Zahra was asleep in her family’s home near Bab al-Azizia when the bombing began. A missile struck a nearby military installation, sending shockwaves that cracked their house’s foundation. Her younger brother, just five, was killed by falling debris.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The operation, which lasted just 12 minutes, resulted in around 100 civilian casualties. Libyan state media broadcast images of damaged homes and wounded children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Granada 1983</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/14-15-granada-1983/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 1983 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/14-15-granada-1983/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;During the U.S. invasion of Grenada (Operation Urgent Fury), airstrikes targeted key facilities held by the Marxist government.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;David Charles, a university janitor, was inside the campus when U.S. aircraft struck the perimeter. Though not directly targeted, the blasts shattered dorm windows and caused several injuries. David helped evacuate wounded students from the rubble.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The operation lasted just days but left lasting political and social consequences. Locals like Charles remained haunted by the sudden eruption of war on their island.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiphong 1972</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/13-17-haiphong-1972/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 1972 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/13-17-haiphong-1972/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Bui Van Phu was working at the port of Haiphong when U.S. bombers launched a series of strikes in 1972. One night, a napalm bomb exploded near a warehouse, setting off a chain reaction that engulfed surrounding buildings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Phu helped evacuate wounded workers and lost two friends in the inferno. After the bombing, he spent weeks removing debris, only to be bombed again days later during another raid.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The U.S. campaign aimed to disrupt North Vietnam’s logistics and shipping, but it severely impacted civilians working in the country’s most critical port city.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hue 1968</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/09-21-hue-1968/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1968 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/09-21-hue-1968/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;During the Tet Offensive, the ancient city of Hue became a battleground. U.S. Marines launched heavy artillery and aerial assaults to recapture it from North Vietnamese and Viet Cong forces.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Nguyen Van Duc was 9 years old when his family&amp;#39;s home in Hue’s old quarter was flattened by an airstrike. His father, a schoolteacher, was killed instantly. Duc and his mother fled through shattered alleyways as firefights echoed in the background.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khe Sanh 1968</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/10-26-khe-sanh-1968/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1968 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/10-26-khe-sanh-1968/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Pham Quang Huy was a porter for the South Vietnamese army stationed near the Khe Sanh combat base when the siege began. U.S. forces dropped more than 100,000 tons of bombs in 77 days—the equivalent of five Hiroshima-level bombs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Huy lost hearing in one ear after a B-52 strike landed too close to his position. He witnessed entire hillsides collapse from the force of the bombardment and saw comrades buried alive in trenches.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Lai 1968</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/11-35-my-lai-1968/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1968 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/11-35-my-lai-1968/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Although not a traditional bombing campaign, My Lai was the site of one of the Vietnam War’s worst atrocities. U.S. troops, under the command of Lt. William Calley, massacred over 500 unarmed civilians. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Do Ba, 10 years old, hid in a ditch with his younger sister. He watched soldiers execute his neighbors at close range. A helicopter crew—Warrant Officer Hugh Thompson and his gunners—landed amid the chaos and stopped further killings by threatening their fellow Americans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saigon 1968</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/12-44-saigon-1968/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1968 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/12-44-saigon-1968/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;During the 1968 Tet Offensive, U.S. forces conducted aerial and artillery bombardments within Saigon to push back insurgents. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Trinh Thi Lan, a nurse working in Cho Ray Hospital, described the chaos as shells landed near the hospital grounds. The maternity ward was evacuated, and Lan helped move newborns into underground shelters. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Although U.S. firepower ultimately repelled the offensive, many neighborhoods were damaged in the crossfire. Lan later testified to international reporters about the trauma inflicted on patients and hospital staff alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hanoi 1965</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/08-18-hanoi-1965/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 1965 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/08-18-hanoi-1965/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Nguyen Thi Thanh was 17 when the first wave of U.S. bombers targeted Hanoi in 1965. During &amp;#34;Operation Rolling Thunder,&amp;#34; her school was struck by a 500-pound bomb. She survived by diving beneath her desk, but 12 classmates were killed instantly. Her brother, drafted into local civil defense, helped clear the rubble.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Between 1965 and 1972, Hanoi faced repeated waves of aerial assault. The most intense came in December 1972 during &amp;#34;Operation Linebacker II,&amp;#34; which dropped over 20,000 tons of bombs on the city in just 12 days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wonsan 1951</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/07-52-wonsan-1951/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1951 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/07-52-wonsan-1951/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Wonsan endured the longest naval blockade and bombardment in modern history. For over 860 days, U.S. Navy ships shelled the port city nearly every day during the Korean War. In tandem, airstrikes leveled much of the urban area.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Han Myong-suk was 10 years old when her school was bombed. She later recalled crawling through rubble to find her cousin, who was buried under debris. Her family relocated inland, where they struggled with starvation and disease.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyongyang 1950</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/06-40-pyongyang-1950/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1950 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/06-40-pyongyang-1950/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;During the Korean War, Pyongyang was subjected to intense aerial bombardment by U.S. forces. In November 1950, the capital was flattened in a series of raids intended to destroy military infrastructure. Survivors describe living in caves and makeshift shelters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Ri Yong-suk, who was 13 at the time, later recounted in interviews that her family spent nearly two years living underground to avoid U.S. airstrikes. Her brother died of illness due to the lack of food and clean water. Her memory of the war was one of constant displacement, hunger, and fear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dresden 1945</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/02-13-dresden-1945/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1945 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/02-13-dresden-1945/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Lothar Metzger was nine years old when the Allied bombing of Dresden began. On the first night, he and his mother fled to a basement shelter as the city was engulfed in flames. They survived the first wave, but when they emerged, they found much of their neighborhood obliterated. The following day, they watched as new waves of bombers returned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The resulting firestorm melted asphalt, suffocated thousands, and consumed entire districts. Metzger and his mother walked for days through the ruins, witnessing piles of bodies laid out in courtyards. His testimony later appeared in multiple postwar documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiroshima 1945</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/03-19-hiroshima-1945/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1945 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/03-19-hiroshima-1945/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;+HUGO_CATEGORIES: World War II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Father John A. Siemes, a Jesuit priest, was residing at the Novitiate of the Society of Jesus in Nagatsuke, approximately two kilometers from Hiroshima&amp;#39;s center. At 8:14 a.m., he witnessed a blinding flash, followed by a wave of heat and a powerful blast that shattered windows and doors. Fires erupted across the city, and soon, streams of injured and burned individuals sought refuge at the Novitiate. Siemes and his colleagues provided first aid, despite limited medical supplies. He later ventured into the city, describing it as a &amp;#34;gigantic burned-out scar,&amp;#34; with countless dead and wounded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nagasaki 1945</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/04-36-nagasaki-1945/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1945 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/04-36-nagasaki-1945/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Masakatsu Obata, 99, was working at the Mitsubishi factory in Nagasaki when the atomic bomb detonated. After an air raid warning subsided, he resumed work, only to be engulfed by a sudden, intense light. The factory’s roof collapsed, and Obata sustained injuries. He sought shelter and encountered a coworker with severe burns, whose skin had melted off. The coworker died three days later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Obata’s family suffered immensely; his sister, who had gone to work that morning, never returned. His parents searched for her remains in vain. Obata himself experienced radiation sickness, including vomiting, hair loss, and bleeding gums. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tokyo 1945</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/05-49-tokyo-1945/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1945 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/05-49-tokyo-1945/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Shizuko Nishio was six years old when Tokyo was engulfed in flames during the U.S. firebombing on March 10, 1945. Anticipating her birthday the next day, she was awakened by air raid sirens. Her father led the family to a nearby primary school for shelter, but it was overcrowded. They moved to another school&amp;#39;s basement, leaving behind her cousin and a nurse. The next day, they learned that the initial shelter had become a death trap, with over 200 people perishing inside. Nishio was the sole survivor among her kindergarten classmates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rouen 1944</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/01-42-rouen-1944/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 1944 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/01-42-rouen-1944/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;In April 1944, weeks before D-Day, the U.S. Army Air Forces launched a bombing raid over Rouen aimed at disrupting German logistics. The bombing inadvertently struck several civilian areas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Jean-Claude Ruel, then a teenager, was caught in the open during the attack. His younger sister was killed instantly by a collapsing wall. Ruel survived by hiding in a ditch but carried shrapnel injuries into adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The bombing campaign, part of the broader Allied strategy to liberate France, caused significant destruction and civilian casualties in occupied cities like Rouen. While ultimately aiding the defeat of Nazi Germany, these operations left lasting scars among French civilians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debug Page</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/debug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page shows debug information for troubleshooting purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
