<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>World War II on Against The Tide</title><link>https://torchscribe.com/tags/world-war-ii/</link><description>Recent content in World War II on Against The Tide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1945 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://torchscribe.com/tags/world-war-ii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>13 Dresden 1945</title><link>https://torchscribe.com/essays/02-13-dresden-1945/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1945 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://torchscribe.com/essays/02-13-dresden-1945/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lothar Metzger was nine years old when the Allied bombing of Dresden began. On the first night, he and his mother fled to a basement shelter as the city was engulfed in flames. They survived the first wave, but when they emerged, they found much of their neighborhood obliterated. The following day, they watched as new waves of bombers returned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The resulting firestorm melted asphalt, suffocated thousands, and consumed entire districts. Metzger and his mother walked for days through the ruins, witnessing piles of bodies laid out in courtyards. His testimony later appeared in multiple postwar documentaries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>49 Tokyo 1945</title><link>https://torchscribe.com/essays/05-49-tokyo-1945/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 1945 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://torchscribe.com/essays/05-49-tokyo-1945/</guid><description>&lt;p>Shizuko Nishio was six years old when Tokyo was engulfed in flames during the U.S. firebombing on March 10, 1945. Anticipating her birthday the next day, she was awakened by air raid sirens. Her father led the family to a nearby primary school for shelter, but it was overcrowded. They moved to another school&amp;rsquo;s basement, leaving behind her cousin and a nurse. The next day, they learned that the initial shelter had become a death trap, with over 200 people perishing inside. Nishio was the sole survivor among her kindergarten classmates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dresden 1945</title><link>https://torchscribe.com/essays/01-42-rouen-1944/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 1944 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://torchscribe.com/essays/01-42-rouen-1944/</guid><description>&lt;p>In April 1944, weeks before D-Day, the U.S. Army Air Forces launched a bombing raid over Rouen aimed at disrupting German logistics. The bombing inadvertently struck several civilian areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jean-Claude Ruel, then a teenager, was caught in the open during the attack. His younger sister was killed instantly by a collapsing wall. Ruel survived by hiding in a ditch but carried shrapnel injuries into adulthood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bombing campaign, part of the broader Allied strategy to liberate France, caused significant destruction and civilian casualties in occupied cities like Rouen. While ultimately aiding the defeat of Nazi Germany, these operations left lasting scars among French civilians.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>